We've already walked through the first two steps in the last video.
在上一节视频中 我们已经了解了前两步
Now I'm going to show you a couple of things you could have experimented with.
现在我会给你展示一些你能够实践的事情
I would like to change the initial quantity value so
我将要改变 quantity 的初始值
that when the app launches it shows up as zero instead of two.
以便当应用启动时 它的值是0 不是2
The way I can do that is to modify this global quantity variable
实现它的方式是修改全局变量 quantity
to be initialized at zero.
初始化为 0
Then the increment and decrement method should work just fine.
increment 和 decrement 方法会正常工作
When the increment method is called,
当调用 increment 方法时
it will use the latest quantity value and just add one.
它会使用最新的 quantity 值 然后加1
When the decrement method is called, it will just decrease the quantity by one.
当调用 decrement 方法时 将 quantity 的值减1
Let's go ahead and try this out now.
我们试一下
That looks weird.
这看起来很奇怪
I wanted it to show up at zero.
我想让它显示 0
If I click the plus button, it's weird, it goes to one,
如果我点击 + 按钮 奇怪的是 它变成了 1
which seems to have decreased it, but now it starts to increase.
看起来减小了 但是它实际上增加了
So it seems like these buttons are working, but for
看起来这些按钮正常工作 但是
some reason the initial value was wrong.
初始化的时候出现了问题
Oh, we forgot to change the activity main layout file.
我们忘记修改 activity_main.xml 布局文件
In this layout we have a text view that says the initial text
在这个布局文件里 我们有一个 TextView
quantity value is two.
初始的 quantity 值是2
That should fix our problem with the two showing up when the app launches.
当应用启动的时候就能修复显示2的问题
Cool. Now it shows up
现在它显示的
as initial quantity of zero.
初始值为0
Then if I hit increase, it updates properly.
然后如果我点击 + 按钮 值的更新是正常的
If I hit decrease, it also updates properly.
然后如果我点击 - 按钮 值的更新是正常的
You can see that it's a little tricky that we have the initial quantity
你能看到有一点棘手的是
value in two places.
我们在两个地方对 quantity 进行初始化
Having two places in the code that represent the same thing
在代码中有两个地方做相同的事情
can be a source of bugs in the future, like we just saw now.
可能会出现 bug 就像我们看到的
An advanced way to solve this problem is to have the main activity actually
解决这个问题的方法是 当应用启动时
display the quantity of zero immediately when the app launches,
在 MainActivity 里立即显示 quantity 的值为 0
instead of relying on the layout to have an initial value.
而不是依赖布局中的初始化
That way the single source of truth would be this global variable.
这种方式会使全局变量成为这个值的唯一来源
But don't worry about that now.
但是你现在不用担心
That's more of an advanced thing that you can do after Lesson 3.
你会在课程三中会学到更好的解决办法
The other way we can experiment with the code is to have the plus button
另一个我们可以实践的事情是 每次点击 + 按钮时
double the number of coffees ordered each time and
咖啡的数量加倍
have the minus button half the number of coffees each time.
每次点击 – 按钮时 咖啡的数量减半
Let's start with an initial quantity of two, so
我们将 quantity 的初始值设置为2
that if we hit the minus button first, we can at least cut this in half once.
以便如果我们点击 – 按钮 我们至少能使咖啡的数量减半
When the increment method is called,
当调用 increment 方法时
we want to double the number of coffees ordered.
我们想使咖啡的数目加倍
We should take the current quantity and then multiply it by two.
我们应该使用当前的 quantity 然后乘以2
That gets updated to be the new quantity value and
然后得到新的 quantity 值并且
then we display that to the screen.
在屏幕上显示
On the other hand, we have the decrement method.
另一方面 我们调用 decrement 方法
For the decrement method, we want to cut the number of coffees ordered in half.
对于 decrement 方法 我们想要咖啡的数目减少一半
So we can take the current quantity and then divide it by two.
所以我们可以获取当前值 然后除以2
That will be the new quantity value.
就会得到新的 quantity 值
And we display that to the screen.
并将它显示在屏幕上
Let's try it out.
我们试一下
You can see how it can be a source of error every time you want
你可以看到 每次你想要更改 quantity 的
to change the initial quantity value.
初始值时 这里都会产生错误
You have to change it in both places.
你需要在两个地方改变它的值
Let's run the app now.
现在我们运行这个应用
Okay.
好
It starts off at an initial quantity of two.
它已经启动 quantity 的初始值是2
If I hit plus, it should double the quantity each time.
如果我点击 + 按钮 quantity 的值每次都会加倍
Cool. And it does.
确实是这样
If I hit the minus button,
如果我点击 – 按钮
it should cut the number of coffees ordered in half each time.
每次它会将咖啡的数目减少一半
And it works.
它做到了
If I run it in the debugger, you can see how it updates the variables each time.
如果我以调试模式运行 你会看到每次变量的值是怎样改变的
The quantity value starts off at two, and then it updates to four.
quantity 的初始值是2 然后它变成了4
And then the quantity starts off at four, and
然后 quantity 的初始值是4
then it updates to eight and so on.
它会变成8 以此类推
I'm sure you came up with much more creative ways to play around with this
我确信你能想到更多创造性的方法来解决
quantity picker.
quantity 更新的问题
Hopefully that helped you better understand the use of global variables.
希望这个能帮助你更好地理解全局变量
But if I hit the order button, it doesn't show me the price for
但是如果我点击 ORDER 按钮 它没有显示
that number of coffees ordered.
订购的咖啡数目的总价
Let's fix that in the next video.
在下一节视频中我们会解决这个问题